softorino.com 2018-12-27

# Privacy policy

###  Contents 

###  Privacy Policy 

Softorino takes your privacy seriously. Privacy policy on this page explains how Softorino treats any personal information that Softorino collects and receives when you are using the Softorino website (“Website”) or products. Please read the content below to learn more about our privacy policy and commitment. 

### Who We are

Softorino, Ltd. ("We" or "Our" or "Us" or "Softorino) collects and uses your Personal Data in accordance with this privacy policy and in compliance with the applicable data protection laws. This policy provides you with the necessary information regarding your rights and our obligations, and explains how, why and when we process your personal data. Softorino, Ltd, is a company registered in Marshall Islands, Ajeltake Road, Majuro, MH 9696, and acts as the data controller when processing your data. 

### Our Privacy Commitment

Softorino does not collect nor process any Personal Data that is not provided by our users specifically, voluntarily and consciously. We guarantee that our staff complies with the strictest standards of safety and confidentiality and that processing of said Personal Data is carried out with total respect of international legislations. 

### What Is Personal Data?

In the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR") personal data is defined as: "…any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person ('data subject'); an identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person”. 

### Information We Use

We take your privacy very seriously and will never disclose, share or sell your data without your consent, unless required to do so by law. We only retain your Personal Data for as long as is necessary and for the purposes specified in this policy. The information we collect helps us develop, deliver, protect, and improve our products, services, content, and customer communications. 

Personal Data is collected and stored if and only if you purchase a product from Softorino, request a trial license key, sign up for a mobile reminder, open a support ticket, or subscribe to our newsletter. We store name & email address that you provide us with, as well as which licenses you purchased and when and how often said licenses were activated. At no point in the purchase process does Softorino access or store your payment details (credit card number or PayPal account details). 

### How We Use It

We process your Personal Data to meet our legal and contractual obligations, and to provide you with our products and services. We will never collect any unnecessary personal data from you and do not process your information in any way, other than as specified in this policy. Softorino’s products can only be used if activated via trial license key or purchased lifetime license key. To run a trial of our products, we must generate a unique activation key generated to you personally and sent to your email. As a part of the product experience, we’ll send a reminder to the email you’ve provided. This is done to make sure trial users aware that their trial has expired. If you purchase a lifetime license of any Softorino products, you will receive on boarding emails & updates created to enhance your experience. The name provided will be used to personalize the on boarding emails. 

We may collect and use your e-mail address to reply to your customer support requests, to send you product updates, or to communicate with you for other important Softorino related information. We may occasionally send you marketing information where we have assessed that it is beneficial to you as a client and in our interests. Where you have consented to us providing you with promotional offers and marketing newsletters, you are free to withdraw this consent at any time. There’s an easy to find Opt-Out button in the emails you may receive from Softorino. 

### Cookies & Anonymous Data

Softorino may use cookies to collect anonymous information such as browser type, operating system version and date of access. Our cookies cannot be used to identify users. A cookie is a little package of information sent to your browser and stored in the hard drive of your computer. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us. We use the information we collect in this manner to better understand our users' interaction with our website and to optimize the user experience. You can disable cookies in your browser settings, but please note that certain features on our website may not be available as a result. 

Here are some examples of non-personal information that we collect – either by ourselves or through the use of third-party services: 

  * When you visit our website, we keep logs of your Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type and language, referring and exit pages, operating system and date/time stamp. We use Google Analytics to collect strictly anonymous information on the usage of our websites and products. This information is processed by Softorino in order to enhance and customize content and user experience. If you’d like to block Google Analytics, follow the instructions here. 
  * In our email communications, we may use other technologies like "pixel tags" and "click-through URLs" in order to determine if an email has been opened and which links have been clicked. This way, we can determine and improve the effectiveness of our communications. Pixel tags are small images shown inside an HTML email; you can disable tracking by disabling HTML in your email client. A link with a click-through URL, when clicked, first sends the user to a web server which records the click, and then to the link's destination. 

### 3rd Party Services

We operate our business in partnership with 3rd parties that operate with the leading standards of privacy applied. Here’s a list of third party services that we use, who they are and what type of data they store. If available, we also include the ability to opt out: 

  1. #### FastSpring

FastSpring is our reseller and all purchases of Softorino products are processed through FastSpring.  
Data they store: e-mail, purchase info & history of Softorino products.  
Privacy Policy: <http://www.fastspring.com/privacy.php>  

  2. #### DevMate

DevMate takes care of our license activations and crash reporting.  
Shared Data: e-mail, owned licenses, trial/activated licenses, license activation history.  
Privacy Policy: <https://devmate.com/policy>  

  3. #### SupportYourApp

SupportYourApp is our customer support provider and platform.  
Shared Data: name, e-mail, phone number, support conversations and purchase history.  
Privacy Policy: <https://supportyourapp.com/privacy-notice/>  

  4. #### MailChimp

MailChimp is our trial automation & mailing list management tool.  
Shared Data: e-mail, name, product license key.  
Privacy Policy: [http://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/)  

###  Links to Other Websites 

Our site may contain links that belong to third parties. Any third party website featured on our site has its own privacy policy. You should check their terms. We do not accept liability or responsibility for their privacy policies, based on our lack of control over these third party links. 

###  Age Limitations 

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 16. If we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under 16, we will promptly delete this information. Parents or guardians can contact us at [privacy@softorino.com](mailto:privacy@softorino.com). 

###  Your Rights 

You have the right to access any Personal Data that we process about you and to request information about: 

  * What personal data we hold about you;
  * Purposes of the processing;
  * The categories of personal data concerned;
  * The recipients to whom the personal data has been/will be disclosed;
  * How long we intend to store your personal data for;
  * If we did not collect the data directly from you, information about the source;
  * If you believe that we hold any incomplete or inaccurate data about you, you have the right to ask us to correct and/or complete the information and we will strive to do so as quickly as possible, unless there is a valid reason for not doing so, at which point you will be notified.
  * You also have the right to be forgotten of your personal data or to restrict processing (where applicable) in accordance with the data protection laws; as well as to object to any direct marketing from us.

Accordingly, you have the right to request access to your data or to instruct us to remove data permanently from our systems by contacting us at [privacy@softorino.com](mailto:privacy@softorino.com). 

Where applicable, you have the right to data portability of your information and the right to be informed about any automated decision-making we may use. If we receive a request from you to exercise any of the above rights, we may ask you to verify your identity before acting on the request; this is to ensure that your data is protected and kept secure. 

As a controller of Softorino customers' personal data, we recognize our responsibility to respect privacy rights and to put in place appropriate standards of data protection. 

####  What’s GDPR? 

The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is a new European privacy regulation which will replace the current EU Data Protection Directive (Directive 95/46/EC). The GDPR aims to strengthen the security and protection of personal data in the EU and harmonize EU data protection law. The GDPR applies to Softorino because we hold and process "personal identifiable data" of EU residents. Personal data is any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person. 

####  What are the benefits for you with GDPR? 

One of the key aspects of the GDPR is that it creates consistency across EU member states on how personal data can be processed, used, and exchanged securely. We able to demonstrate security of the data we are processing and our compliance with GDPR on a continual basis, by implementing and regularly reviewing robust technical and organizational measures, as well as compliance policies. 

####  Data Processing Agreements (DPA) 

Softorino uses 3rd to process personal data that we may collect and to comply with the GDPR requirements, we have a DPA in place with all 3rd party services we use. 

###  Confidentiality & Security 

All communications between your web browser and Softorino, as well as between our software products and our servers, are secured by strong SSL encryption. Furthermore, access to Personal Data is restricted to employees directly involved in customer support and analytics – they have been trained to observe our strict standards of confidentiality and respect. 

###  Changes to this Privacy Policy 

We’d like you to be fully updated of any changes made to this page. Which is why we’ll send an annoying email informing you of substantive changes. I mean, we realize that you won’t be keeping your eye on this page that often. 

###  Questions & Support 

If you have questions or wish to give us feedback on our current Privacy Policy, please contact us at [privacy@softorino.com](mailto:privacy@softorino.com).
